# Milena Georgieva

Sofia, Bulgaria

© 0877514363

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/milena-georgieva95

https://github.com/MilenaGeorgieva95



https://milena-s-react-portfolio.web.app

# **Profile**

Junior Software Developer with over two years of academic experience creating projects and solving tasks using HTML, CSS, ReactJS, JavaScript, Node.js and Express. Currently at the end of a Full-Stack JavaScript Web Developer program at SoftUni. Experienced in working with databases such as MongoDB and MySQL, version control with GitHub, and styling with Tailwind, CSS, and Bootstrap. Eager to contribute to collective success, through innovation, hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Proficient English speaker with a positive approach to tasks, working well under pressure, deadline orientated, ambitious with a hands on approach.

# **Education and Qualifications**

#### March 2023 - Present

# Software University (SoftUni) | JavaScript Web Developer

At SoftUni, I developed modern, practical programming skills under the guidance of tutors who lead real-world software development teams. I gained knowledge in best coding practices, Object-Oriented and Functional Programming, database architecture and error handling. I worked on multiple Single-Page Application projects using JavaScript, ReactJS, and RESTful APIs focusing on real-world scenarios such as building forums and e-commerce platforms.

### • Key Projects:

- Sprout Hub: I created a gardening forum app, which provides an interactive platform for users to create, manage, and engage with content, including account creation, authentication, and session management, creating posts, likes and comments. Sprout Hub is a Single-Page ReactJS Application which connects to the SoftUni Practice Server as the Back-End and is deployed using Firebase, Docker and Google Cloud Platform.
- Veluxe Motors: Using ReactJS, I made a car rental app that offers an interactive platform enabling users to create car listings, make bookings, search for available vehicles by location, set up accounts, manage their profiles, and interact with content such as special offers and memberships.
- Sole Mates: I build a blog application incorporating REST, CRUD, Authentication and Search functionality
  as part of the JS Applications Module at SoftUni. I utilized page.js and lit-html libraries and deployed the
  app on GitHub Pages.
- MagmaHaven: I created a Multi-Page Application using Express, Express-Handlebars and Node.js as part
  of the JS Back-End Module at SoftUni and connected it to MongoDB with Mongoose. To manage the user
  data, I used Bcrypt, JsonWebToken and cookie-parser enabling secure registration and login/logout
  functionality.
- **Key Modules:** React.js, JS Back-End, HTML and CSS, MySQL, JS Applications, JS Advanced, Programming Fundamentals with JavaScript, Programming Basics with JavaScript

#### Oct 2022 - Mar 2023

#### **UDEMY** | Web Developer Bootcamp

- I gained knowledge of core programming concepts and understanding of how key technologies integrate to build modern applications.
- Key Projects: Museum of Candy, Photo Blog, ToDo List, Score Keeper
- Key Modules: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Forms and Tables, Loops, DOM Events, Flexbox, Bootstrap

#### June 2011 - June 2015

#### Coventry University, Coventry, UK| Bachelor of Arts

• Key Modules: Fashion Design, History of Arts, Marketing, Social Media Platforms and Communication, Pattern Making and Materials

#### Sep 2005 - May 2010

# National School of Fine Arts "Ilya Petrov" | Sofia, Bulgaria

- A-levels equivalents: Biology (A\*), Bulgarian Language and Literature (A\*)
- AS-levels equivalents: English (A), Mathematics (A)

# **Professional Experience**

#### June 2016 - Jan 2023

### Specsavers, Coventry | Optical Assistant

Organised appointments, managed time efficiently preparing paperwork, pretesting and frame styling.

# Apr 2014 - June 2016

### McDonald's, Coventry | Shift-Manager

Supervised and set targets to a team, aiming to meet customer expectations and personal growth goals.

# Sept 2013 - Sept 2014

### Assistant Producer | The English Theatre of Rome, Rome, Italy

• Key responsibilities: Marketing and Design, Costume Design, Website and Social Media Manager, Lights Operator, Decor Design.

### Apr 2010 - June 2014

### Pomorie, Bulgaria | Hotel Receptionist

Booked in guests, tracked reservations, developed problem solving and organisational skills.

# **Professional Skills**

- **Web Developer Software:** Knowledge in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, NPM, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Atlas, MySQL, MySQL Workbench, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind.
- **Programming concepts:** Excellent understanding in AJAX, REST, Object-Oriented Programming, database management, cloud computing, GitBash and GitHub.
- Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Teams, Outlook.
- Design Skills: Strong ground in UI/UX design techniques, Photoshop, Illustrator and Figma.
- Management: Shift-manager in a retail company.
- **Licenses:** British passport.

### Languages

- English: Full professional proficiency
- Bulgarian: Native speaker

#### Interests and Activities

- Drawing: Competed in several competitions, winning one international and two national awards
- Warwick Dragon Boat Festival (2019): Participated in a rowing race for charity